<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://junlanlu.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://junlanlu.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-04-04T01:34:19+00:00</updated><id>https://junlanlu.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">creating my first full-stack web application</title><link href="https://junlanlu.github.io/posts/2023/collegeshunt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="creating my first full-stack web application" /><published>2023-04-27T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-27T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://junlanlu.github.io/posts/2023/collegeshunt</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://junlanlu.github.io/posts/2023/collegeshunt/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve always been passionate about technology and education. I recently decided to channel this passion into creating a web application called <a href="https://collegeshunt.com">collegeshunt.com</a>, which aims to help folks find the most prestigious colleges based on their preferences.</p>

<h2 id="my-thoughts-on-prestige">My thoughts on prestige</h2>

<p>In my perspective, the concept of prestige in higher education should be approached with a balanced mindset that acknowledges its importance while remaining grounded in reality. Prestige is undeniably intertwined with academic reputation, alumni networks, and the overall educational experience, yet it remains a multifaceted and often subjective notion. As an advocate for well-rounded decision-making, I believe prestige can provide valuable insights but should not overshadow other crucial factors such as personal values, academic interests, and individual aspirations.</p>

<h2 id="the-idea">The Idea</h2>

<p>The idea was born from <a href="https://prestigehunt.com">prestigehunt.com</a>, a website that ranks companies by prestige. In fact, I ripped off most of their front-end.</p>

<p>This could also be applied to institutions of higher education, as traditional rankings often don’t provide the complete picture, and there’s a need for a more dynamic and community-driven platform. With this website, users can contribute to the rankings by participating in head-to-head (H2H) prestige matches, creating a more accurate and constantly evolving list of top colleges. Plus, I think it would be funny to see the results.</p>

<h2 id="the-tech-stack">The Tech Stack</h2>

<p>I built a single-page application using React for the front-end and Firebase for the back-end. React’s component-based architecture and Firebase’s real-time database capabilities made it an excellent choice for creating a responsive and interactive user experience.</p>

<h2 id="challenges-and-solutions">Challenges and Solutions</h2>

<p>One of the main challenges I encountered during development was that I did not know much about web development. I knew almost nothing about React, Node.js, and databases. I had to figure out how to build this damn thing in the shortest time possible. Conveniently, I generally knew from the front-end what was required of the back-end. The challenge was to figure out how to properly structure the back-end code to fulfill the requests of the front-end client.</p>

<p>To overcome these challenges, I used <a href="https://chat.openai.com/">ChatGPT</a> and <a href="https://github.com/features/copilot">Github Copilot</a>. It saved me a TON of time. Since I knew how the backend should generally behave (and it wasn’t super complicated), they got about 90 percent of the code correct. Being a complete noob, I also wasn’t aware that Firestore had a limit of 500 actions (read, write, or delete operations) per transaction. This limitation posed a challenge when scaling my application to handle hundreds of head-to-head matches. It required me to use batched writes instead.</p>

<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Building this website has been an incredibly rewarding experience, as I’ve learned a lot about React, Firebase, and ChatGPT prompting. Finally, don’t take the rankings too seriously.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects" /><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[building a web-app to rank colleges]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">investing in pokémon sealed product</title><link href="https://junlanlu.github.io/posts/2023/pokemon-investing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="investing in pokémon sealed product" /><published>2023-04-20T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-20T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://junlanlu.github.io/posts/2023/pokemon-investing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://junlanlu.github.io/posts/2023/pokemon-investing/"><![CDATA[<p>I grew up in the era of Pokémon, and as a kid, I was absolutely captivated by it. From playing the Pokémon games on my DS to opening up Pokémon cards at my local card shop, Pokémon was a huge part of my life. As I got older, I kept my love for Pokémon, and it eventually led me to start investing in Pokémon cards.</p>

<h2 id="why-pokémon-is-a-decent-investment">Why Pokémon is a Decent Investment</h2>

<p>The Pokémon franchise has been around for more than 25 years, and it’s still going strong. The brand has a massive, loyal fan base that spans multiple generations. The scarcity and demand for certain rare cards have resulted in their value appreciating over time. With a stable fan base, nostalgia, and limited supply, it makes sense that the prices of rare cards and items would increase. More specifically, sealed booster boxes, have a unique appeal to collectors and investors due to their rarity and the potential for valuable cards inside. As these boxes become harder to find over time (they’re either opened or destroyed), their scarcity increases, driving up their value. Moreover, the unopened boxes retain an air of mystery, with collectors speculating about the possibility of finding rare or highly sought-after cards within. Also, many people who grew up with Pokémon have fond memories of opening packs, and the desire to relive those moments can create additional demand for sealed product. I see it as investing in slot machines because you know people will want to gamble.</p>

<h2 id="what-i-am-collecting">What I am collecting</h2>

<p>I am collecting sealed WOTC and EX booster boxes. Booster boxes, unlike many other sealed products, don’t take up much space, but contain a lot of value inside. They’re a bit more liquid than individual PSA slabs, making them easier to sell later on. There’s also a healthy market of collectors, investors, and box-breakers.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="fun" /><category term="fun" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[investing in Pokémon cards]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">keeping track of online resources</title><link href="https://junlanlu.github.io/posts/2023/resources/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="keeping track of online resources" /><published>2023-04-20T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-20T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://junlanlu.github.io/posts/2023/resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://junlanlu.github.io/posts/2023/resources/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="my-resources">My resources</h1>

<p>I find a lot of online resources that help me learn. Unfortunately, I don’t get to check them all out because I have a short attention span. So, I will keep a running list of them here.</p>
<h2 id="computer-science">Computer Science</h2>
<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="https://github.com/ossu/computer-science">Open source online university (OSSU)</a></strong>
    <h2 id="machine-learning">Machine Learning</h2>
  </li>
</ol>

<h2 id="computer-vision">Computer Vision</h2>
<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="https://stanford.edu/class/ee367/">Stanford EE367 Computational Imaging</a></strong></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@firstprinciplesofcomputerv3258">First Principles of CV (youtube)</a>
    <h2 id="mri">MRI</h2>
  </li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/LarsonLab/MRI-education-resources">MRI educational resources</a>
    <h2 id="statistics">Statistics</h2>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="https://www.bcfoltz.com/stats-101/">Brandon Foltz Statistics 101</a></strong></li>
</ol>

<h2 id="math">Math</h2>

<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cx5Z-OslNWE&amp;list=PLUl4u3cNGP63oMNUHXqIUcrkS2PivhN3k">Matrix Methods by Professor Strang</a></strong></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Di9f47LAzHQ&amp;list=PLRPU00LaonXQ27RBcq6jFJnyIbGw5azOI">Convex Optimization</a></li>
  <li>[Score Models] (A Pedagogical Introduction to Score Models)
    <h2 id="blogs">Blogs</h2>
  </li>
  <li><a href="https://e2eml.school/blog.html#121">Brandon Rohrer</a></li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="resources" /><category term="resources" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[a list of resources I've come across]]></summary></entry></feed>